Hello, everyone. Welcome to today's lecture. Today we are going to wrap up the discussion
大家好，欢迎来到今天的讲座。今天我们将结束讨论。
about the performance and then we are going to spend the main bulk of the lecture on file
关于表现，然后我们将在讲座的主要部分讨论文件。
systems. So let me start. So just to recap from last week, last week we talked a little
关于系统。那么让我开始吧。上周我们谈了一点内容，让我来回顾一下。
bit about performance and this is one way to model the performance in particular for
性能方面的一点，这是一种特别用于建模性能的方法之一。
something like a network. And we are talking then that, for instance, if you send a packet
像一个网络一样。然后我们在讨论，例如，如果你发送一个数据包
with a certain number of bits, say small b, and the network capacity is capital B bits
具有一定数量的比特，比如小写b，并且网络容量为大写B比特。
per second, then this is a formula for latency. You have a factor S, which is overhead to
每秒钟，这是延迟的一个公式。你有一个因子S，它是额外开销。
send that packet, for instance, of the system call, and then plus a variable part, which
发送那个数据包，例如系统调用，然后再加上一个可变部分，其中
is b is the number of bits in the packet over the capacity of the link, capital B. This
是的，b是数据包中的比特数，超过了链路的容量，即大写字母B。
formula also works reasonably well for transferring data from the disk. In this case, the S, it
公式也相对较好地适用于从磁盘传输数据。在这种情况下，S，它
represents the rotation latency plus seek time. So this is one and this is a formula
表示旋转延迟加寻道时间。所以这是一个，这是一个公式。
for the latency and you see here is shown on this plot with a blue line. So the intercept
对于延迟，你可以在这个图上看到以蓝线表示。因此，截距是
of the blue line with the y-axis represents the S, so in this case it's 1000 microseconds
蓝线与y轴的交点表示S，所以在这种情况下是1000微秒。
and then here the slope represents the bandwidth of the particular link. So in this particular
然后这里的斜率代表了特定链接的带宽。所以在这个特定的情况下，斜率表示了带宽。
case, we are going to have a link of 100 Gbps, S was 1000 microseconds or one milliseconds,
在这种情况下，我们将拥有一个100 Gbps的链接，S为1000微秒或一毫秒。
and then b is here on the y-axis. So on b it's 5000 bits, then you are going to get
然后b在y轴上。所以在b上是5000个比特，然后你会得到什么？
the corresponding 5000 over, I think that should be bytes, it's 500,000 divided by
对应的是5000多，我认为应该是字节，它是500,000除以多少？
125 megabytes per second, that will give you 4000 microseconds or four milliseconds. And
每秒125兆字节，这将给你4000微秒或四毫秒。而且
if you add to S, which is one millisecond, you are going to get five milliseconds or
如果你将S增加1毫秒，你将得到5毫秒或者
5000 microseconds. Okay, and then the other important metrics here is the effective bandwidth,
5000微秒。好的，然后这里的另一个重要指标是有效带宽。
which is basically, okay, if I'm sending a packet of this length, what is the effective
长度的数据包，如果我发送一个这样的数据包，那么有效的是什么？
bandwidth for sending that packet? And that obviously is a packet size, in this case b,
发送该数据包的带宽是多少？显然这是一个数据包的大小，在这种情况下是b。
over the time it takes to send the packet, which it does include S, the fixed overhead,
在发送数据包所需的时间内，其中包括S，即固定的开销。
and this is a formula B capital B times S over b small b plus one. Okay. You notice
这是一个公式，大写字母B乘以S除以小写字母b加一。好的。你注意到了吗？
that if S is zero, then the effective bandwidth is equal with capital B, which is expected,
如果S为零，则有效带宽等于大写字母B，这是预期的。
right? Because there is no fixed overhead, then the effective bandwidth, you can send
对吗？因为没有固定的开销，所以有效带宽可以发送。
data as fast as the capacity of the link. And one important metric here is about, it's
数据的传输速度取决于链路的容量。这里有一个重要的指标，它是关于...
a half power bandwidth, and half power bandwidth is a way to think about it, is basically what
半功率带宽，半功率带宽是一种思考方式，基本上就是这样理解的。
is the size of the packet in this case I need to send such that the effective bandwidth
在这种情况下，我需要发送的数据包大小是为了使有效带宽达到最大。
to be half of the capacity of the link, right? So the overhead is not that very high. Overhead
是链路容量的一半，对吗？所以开销并不是非常高。开销
just cuts my capacity to half, right? And here is red, you can see the curve, this curve
只是将我的容量减少了一半，对吗？这里是红色的，你可以看到曲线，这个曲线
is red, is the effective bandwidth, again versus the capacity of the link. And when
是红色的，是有效带宽，再次与链路容量进行比较。当
the number of bits is zero, obviously here you have effective bandwidth, it's zero. Okay.
比特数为零，显然这里的有效带宽也是零。好的。
And on this plot here on the right, this is a plot which has two y-axis on the left hand
这个右边的图表上，有两个左侧的y轴。
side is the latency, the blue one, the blue curve, the blue line, and on the right hand
右边是延迟，蓝色的，蓝色曲线，蓝色线条，右手边。
side you are going to have the bandwidth, effective bandwidth, which is a red line.
你将拥有带宽，有效带宽，即红线。
Any questions? So next, remember that we also did a little bit of queuing theory, mostly
有任何问题吗？接下来，记住我们也稍微讲了一点排队论，主要是为了
providing you some formulas, so just summarize them here. And as you know, this topic is
为您提供一些公式，所以在这里简要总结一下。正如您所知，这个话题是...
covered. This is part of the exam, the midterm topics. And so you may get the problem, which
已覆盖。这是考试的一部分，是期中考试的题目。所以你可能会遇到这个问题，它是关于哪些内容的？
is about queuing theory or about performance, cyber performance. So anyway, so here you
这是关于排队理论还是关于性能，网络性能。无论如何，这里你可以
remember that this is a queuing model, obviously it's called a queuing model, so for a reason,
记住这是一个排队模型，显然它被称为排队模型，所以有其原因。
it has a queue. So you have a bunch of requests here with the arrival rate lambda, lambda
它有一个队列。所以你在这里有一堆请求，到达率为lambda，lambda。
is the number of requests, average number of requests per second arriving to the queue,
请问您是指请求的数量，每秒到达队列的平均请求数量吗？
and the requests are removed from the queue as fast as they can be processed by a server.
并且这些请求会尽可能快地从队列中移除，以便服务器进行处理。
And the server processes each request at the service rate mu, and mu is one over the service
并且服务器以服务速率mu处理每个请求，其中mu等于服务时间的倒数。
time, how long it takes to service a particular request. So the way to think about if the
时间，完成特定请求需要多长时间。因此，思考的方式是，如果
server takes 100 milliseconds to serve a request, then obviously mu is one second over 100 milliseconds
服务器需要100毫秒来处理一个请求，那么显然1秒等于100毫秒。
is 10 because you can serve 10 requests per second. So then another important parameter
是10，因为你可以每秒处理10个请求。所以另一个重要的参数是什么？
is square coefficient of variance to characterize the systems and the server utilization. The
方差系数是用来描述系统和服务器利用率的。
server utilization is basically the average arrival rate over the average service rate.
服务器利用率基本上是平均到达率除以平均服务率。
And fundamentally you do want these parameters to be less than one because this would mean
而且从根本上说，你确实希望这些参数小于一，因为这意味着
that the system is in the stable regime, that any stable regime, if the arrival rate is
稳定状态是指系统处于稳定的运行状态，对于任何稳定状态而言，如果到达率是
lower than the service capacity about how fast the request can be served. If you send
低于服务能力，关于请求能够被快速处理的速度。如果你发送
more, obviously the system will not be in a stable regime, which means that the queries,
更多，显然系统不会处于稳定状态，这意味着查询，
the queue will grow indefinitely, right? As more requests come in and the system cannot
队列会无限增长，对吗？随着更多的请求进来，系统无法处理。
keep up with serving these requests. And all the results typically in the queuing theory
跟上处理这些请求的速度。而且所有的结果通常符合排队论的原理。
assumes that rho is less than one. And then the parameters you want to compute is the
假设rho小于一。然后你想要计算的参数是什么？
time you spend in the queue, right? We know how long it takes a request to be served.
你说的是在队列中花费的时间，对吗？我们知道一个请求需要多长时间才能被处理。
So it's t serve. So now we need to understand how long it takes a request to spend in the
服务器上。所以现在我们需要了解一个请求在服务器上花费多长时间。
queue. So then by adding the do, we know the service time for the queuing time, we know
排队。因此，通过添加“do”，我们知道排队时间的服务时间，我们知道
how much a request spend in the entire system, which is what matters from the user perspective.
整个系统中一个请求花费多少时间，这是用户关注的重点。
And then we also want to learn about the little law and the little law allows you to compute
然后我们还想了解一下小定律，小定律可以帮助你计算。
the queue length by just multiplying the mean arrival rate plus the time average time spent
队列长度可以通过将平均到达率乘以平均等待时间来计算。
in the queue. And this is some of the results we went over last time. So it's again, this
在队列中。这是我们上次讨论的一些结果。所以这次又是这样。
is a recap, which may help you for the tomorrow's midterm. And t queue is for MM1 queue, which
是一个复习，可能对你明天的期中考试有帮助。而t队列是用于MM1队列的。
is remember an MM1 queue is one of the simplest queues out there. It has one is for means
记住，MM1队列是最简单的队列之一。它有一个用于表示的含义。
that it has one server, m, the first time refers to the distribution of the arrival
它只有一个服务器m，第一次提到的是到达的分布。
rate. So this means that the intervals between two consecutive requests arriving is exponentially
速率。这意味着连续两个请求到达之间的时间间隔是指数分布的。
distributed or it's also called Poisson distribution of the arrival rate. And also the service
分布或者也被称为泊松分布的到达率。还有服务。
time is exponentially distributed. It's again the time it takes to serve it's exponentially
时间服从指数分布。这是再次服务所需的时间。
distributed. And the formula here is this serve times row over one minus row. And for
分布式。这里的公式是服务时间乘以流量除以1减去流量。而对于
a more general queue where the serving time, it's general, it's just characterized by the
一个更通用的队列，服务时间是通用的，只是由...来特征化。
C, we know only about the square coefficient of variance. You have a very similar formula,
C，我们只知道方差的平方系数。你有一个非常相似的公式，
only the second parameters is a formula it's different. But the real main point to notice
只有第二个参数是一个不同的公式。但真正需要注意的主要点是什么？
about this formula are this last term, which is row over one minus row. And this capture
关于这个公式，最后一项是row除以一减row。而这个capture
what I said earlier, that if row is should be less than one, that if it's equal or greater
我之前说的是，如果行数应该小于一，如果它等于或大于
than one, then the system will not be in a stable region. Right? And this is a plot showing
如果超过一个，则系统将不处于稳定区域。对吗？这是一个显示的图表。
you roughly how the response time and the service time is looking versus throughput
你大致看一下响应时间和服务时间与吞吐量的关系如何。
or utilization versus row. So on the x-axis is basically row is from zero, say to one,
或者是利用率与行之间的关系。因此，x轴基本上是行，从零到一。
and this is a response time. The response time is a queuing time plus the service time.
这是一个响应时间。响应时间是排队时间加上服务时间。
And as a time, as a row goes to one, this is going to be dominated by the queuing time
而作为一个时间，随着一行的进行，这将会被排队时间所主导。
because the queuing time is going to grow one row. It's close to one, then this goes
因为排队时间将增加一行。它接近一行，然后这个就会发生。
to infinity. Okay. So any questions? Okay. So now let's talk about how we are going to
无限。好的。有什么问题吗？好的。现在让我们来谈谈我们要如何做。
optimize the performance and what are the ways to optimize it. And this is what we are
优化性能以及优化的方式有哪些。这是我们正在做的事情。
going to discuss over the next several slides. And again, if you look about for an IO device,
接下来几张幻灯片将要讨论的内容。再次提醒，如果你正在寻找一个输入/输出设备，
you are going to have the user stress. This is where the program is running. Then you
你将要让用户感到压力。这是程序运行的地方。然后你会
are going to send requests, say read or write from this particular file, which is from that
你将要发送请求，比如读或写这个特定文件，该文件来自那个地方。
particular one particular device. And these requests are queued and then are submitted
特定的一个特定设备。这些请求会被排队，然后提交。
to a controller and the controller is going to program the IO device to read and write
给一个控制器，控制器将编程输入/输出设备进行读写操作。
the particular data. Okay. And so how you are going to improve this system? Well, there
特定的数据。好的。那么你打算如何改进这个系统？嗯，
are a few ways. One speed, right? You can make everything faster. Each of these components,
有几种方法。一个是速度，对吧？你可以让一切变得更快。这些组件中的每一个，
you can make it faster. You reduce the overhead of the context switching. You have also some
你可以加快速度。你可以减少上下文切换的开销。你还有一些其他的方法。
context switching here of the controller and of the device. You buy a disk which rotates
在控制器和设备之间进行上下文切换。你购买了一个旋转的磁盘。
faster with a lower seek time. Another way is parallelism. It's basically, you know,
更快速且寻找时间更短。另一种方式是并行处理。基本上，你知道的，
you can parallelize. You can have, you know, inside, you can have multiple queues if the
你可以并行化。你可以在内部使用多个队列。
queue observations are expensive. Or instead of an IO device, you may have multiple IO
队列观测是昂贵的。或者，您可以拥有多个输入/输出设备，而不是一个输入/输出设备。
requests. You can, for instance, as you know, probably you can have two disks and then you
请求。你可以，比如说，你知道的，可能你可以有两个磁盘，然后你可以
are going to strive the data across disks. So therefore, or you just partition the data
将数据分布在多个磁盘上。所以，你可以选择将数据进行分区，或者只是将数据进行分割。
between disks. So when different requests can run at the same time on if they are going
在磁盘之间。因此，如果不同的请求可以同时运行，它们就可以在磁盘上运行。
to request data on different disks. Then is overlap, right? So this applies to different
请求不同磁盘上的数据。那么是否存在重叠呢？所以这适用于不同的
parts of this kind of pipeline. So for instance, for the thread, you send a request, you are
部分这种类型的管道。例如，对于线程，你发送一个请求，你正在
waiting for the request, you can do some useful work instead of just waiting. The same thing
等待请求时，你可以做一些有用的工作，而不仅仅是等待。同样的事情。
here is like for the controller, as you program the current request and you program the IO
这里是控制器的链接，你可以编写当前请求并编写输入输出。
device to ask to satisfy the current request. Once you do that and you send the request
设备来询问是否满足当前请求。一旦你这样做并发送请求。
to IO device, then you can process the next request. The one important aspect here is
将数据发送到输入/输出设备，然后您可以处理下一个请求。这里有一个重要的方面是
that one way to look at this pipeline, say you want to improve the performance here,
这是一种看待这个管道的方式，假设你想要改善这里的性能，
what you are going to do is the engineering way to look about and or software engineering
你要做的是以工程的方式来看待和处理软件工程问题。
way, the sound way to do it is to look what is the bottlenecks are, which is a bottleneck,
嗯，正确的做法是找出瓶颈所在，确定是哪个环节存在瓶颈。
which is a slowest part in this chain. And then you are going to focus on that bottleneck
这个链条中哪个部分是最慢的。然后你将专注于解决这个瓶颈。
part to improve the performance, because if you improve the performance of something which
部分需要改进的是性能，因为如果你改进了某个东西的性能，那么
is already fast, not the slowest link in the chain, then the end-to-end performance will
是已经很快了，不是链条中最慢的环节，那么端到端的性能将会
not improve much. And remember, the queues are here to absorb the burst. The queue sees
没有太大改善。记住，队列的作用是吸收突发情况。队列会看到
that because the requests are not going where, you know, are equally distanced in time, they
这是因为请求并没有按照相等的时间间隔发送出去，你知道的。
can arrive in a bunch of requests at the same time. So the controller cannot serve on this
可以同时到达一大堆请求。所以控制器无法处理这个。
bunch of requests at the same time. So you need to then queue them because if they don't
同时有很多请求。所以你需要将它们排队，因为如果不这样做的话，可能会导致混乱。
have a queue, you need to drop on the floor of the request, you are going to fail satisfying
你需要排队，把请求放在地上，你将无法满足要求。
the request. And finally, another thing we didn't discuss last time, it is one other
请求。最后，还有一件上次我们没有讨论的事情，还有一个。
techniques in this kind of systems, it's admission control. The admission control basically says,
在这种系统中的技术之一就是准入控制。准入控制基本上是指，
look, and in admission control, why you have admission control in general, is that you
看，关于入场控制，为什么一般会有入场控制，这是因为你需要确保只有符合条件的人才能进入。
basically admission control says that I refuse to, I'm telling you this request I cannot
基本上，准入控制意味着我拒绝，我告诉你，我无法处理这个请求。
handle. Okay? So the thread wants to submit a request and I'm saying, you know, the controller
处理。好吗？所以这个线程想要提交一个请求，我在说，你知道的，控制器
or the queue itself saying I can no longer enqueue this request, come later. And this
或者队列本身说我不能再将这个请求加入队列，请稍后再来。而这个
also typically happens if we want to ensure to limit, to provide guarantees in terms of
还有一种情况是，如果我们想要确保限制并提供保证的话，通常会发生这种情况。
the end-to-end latency of end-to-end response time. Okay? In order to provide, so basically
端到端响应时间的端到端延迟。好吗？为了提供，基本上
saying if I'm going to accept the request, I'm going to guarantee that I'm going to serve
如果我要接受这个请求，我会保证我会履行。
this request in say 100 milliseconds. Right? If I cannot, if there is no admission control,
这个请求在100毫秒内完成，对吗？如果我不能完成，如果没有准入控制，
then I cannot make that guarantee because if there are a lot of requests coming, which
那么我无法做出那个保证，因为如果有很多请求过来的话，那就
exceeds the capacity of my system, I cannot guarantee that each request is going to be
超出了我的系统容量，我无法保证每个请求都会被处理。
processed within 100 milliseconds. Okay? So admission control place is hand in hand with
在100毫秒内处理。好吗？所以入场控制与...手牵手。
limiting the delay if you want to have guarantees on the end-to-end delay. Any questions? Can
如果你想要对端到端延迟有保证，就需要限制延迟。有什么问题吗？
you give an example from real life where the admission control is employed?
在现实生活中，一个应用了准入控制的例子是机场安检。机场安检是为了确保乘客和机组人员的安全，防止危险物品和违禁品进入飞机。在安检过程中，乘客需要通过身份验证、行李检查和身体安检等步骤，以确保他们符合安全要求并且没有携带危险物品。这种准入控制的实施可以有效地保护航空运输系统的安全。
Any? Example? Any? Example? Any? Example? Any? Example? Any? Example? Any? Example?
任何？例子？任何？例子？任何？例子？任何？例子？任何？例子？任何？例子？
Okay. Yes. Red lights on the entrance of the highway. That's exactly, that's a great example.
好的。是的。高速公路入口处的红灯。那确实是个很好的例子。
And real time systems, yes. Although I was, that's, I wouldn't call it real time life.
而且实时系统，是的。虽然我是这样的，但我不会称之为实时生活。
Red lights on the entrance of the highway. That's a great example. And there are many
红灯在高速公路入口处。这是一个很好的例子。而且还有很多。
other examples. Like for instance, in during when there are more restriction on during
其他例子。比如，在有更多限制的期间。
COVID during the pandemics, you know, some shops, you limit the number of customers who
COVID-19疫情期间，你知道的，一些商店限制了顾客的数量。
are inside. So in order to make sure that they can keep distance among themselves, there
是在室内。因此为了确保他们能保持彼此之间的距离，他们需要
are even more obvious examples. Like when you fly on a plane, here is admission control.
还有更明显的例子。比如当你乘坐飞机时，这里就有入场控制。
It's your seat, right? You cannot, it's not like in a bus in which you, you know, there
是你的座位，对吗？你不能坐在那里，这不像公交车上那样，你知道的，那里
is no admission control anyone can get in. Well, I guess it's a natural one. No longer
没有入场控制，任何人都可以进来。嗯，我猜这是一种自然现象。不再
people who are no longer fit in a bus and you know, it's, that's a natural pushback
那些不再适合坐公交车的人，你知道，这是一种自然的反弹。
mechanism. But yeah, there are many examples in real life where you are having this so
机制。但是是的，在现实生活中有很多例子，你会遇到这种情况。
to speak admission control. Ha ha, Berkeley course waitlist. That's a great one. Yes,
说到录取控制，哈哈，伯克利的课程候补名单。真是个好笑的事情。是的，
Richard, that's great. Okay. Thank you. So any of these performance highest, remember,
理查德，太好了。好的，谢谢。所以这些表演中有任何一个是最高的，记住，
obviously, when there are sequential reads where, and this is subtle and we are going
显然，当存在连续读取时，这是微妙的，我们正在进行中。
to see this is a, for, you know, the next, for the next few slides, there is another one.
看到这个是一个，对于，你知道的，下一个，接下来几张幻灯片，还有一个。
There is so much work. You get so many requests. You can piggyback, you basically, you can
有这么多工作。你收到这么多请求。你可以跟着做，基本上，你可以
have so many requests, but can reorder the request says that you can serve this request
有很多请求，但可以重新排序请求，说你可以处理这个请求。
much more effectively. We'll, we'll, we'll see that in a, in a bit. Now, if the system
更加有效地运作。我们会在一会儿看到。现在，如果系统
is mostly idle, it's perfectly fine to be inefficient. No one cares. Right. And, but
大部分时间都是闲置的，效率低下也完全没关系。没人在意。对吧。然后，但是
First, this is an important point, right?
首先，这是一个重要的观点，对吗？
When you have a burst,
当你爆发时，
meaning that you get more requests
意思是你会收到更多的请求。
than the system can handle.
超出系统处理能力的范围。
So you need to queue those.
所以你需要排队。
It's both as threat, or it should be threat there,
这既是威胁，或者应该是威胁。
because they can increase the latency, right?
因为它们可以增加延迟，对吗？
Because you can queue these requests.
因为你可以将这些请求排队。
But it's also an opportunity
但这也是一个机会
because you can do this piggybacking.
因为你可以借助这个来做。
You can, again, reorder the request,
你可以再次重新排序请求，
as you'll see in a few slides,
正如你将在几张幻灯片中看到的，
or you can do batching.
或者你可以进行批处理。
Batching meanings, you can, for instance,
批量处理的意思是，你可以，例如，
you have many requests,
你有很多请求。
you can do one context switching or function calls.
你可以进行一次上下文切换或函数调用。
You can think about, you can do one context switching
你可以考虑一下，你可以进行一次上下文切换。
to handle multiple of these requests at the same time.
同时处理多个这样的请求。
So you amortize the context switching
所以你将上下文切换分摊。
across multiple requests.
跨多个请求。
You can also waste the space for speed.
你也可以浪费空间来换取速度。
Like for instance, you can,
例如，你可以，
you know, when you write on the disk,
你知道，当你在磁盘上写入时，
like, let's see, what will be a good examples?
好的，让我想想，有什么好的例子呢？
Yeah, you can have, for instance,
是的，你可以有，例如，
like for instance, for page tables.
比如说，就拿页表来说。
For page tables, you can have additional hash maps,
对于页表，你可以有额外的哈希映射。
which you are going to keep in order to locate,
你将保留哪个以便定位？
to map the pages, the virtual pages,
将页面映射为虚拟页面。
to the page numbers, to the physical page numbers.
到页码，到物理页码。
Another way to do it is to increase the size of the TLB.
另一种方法是增加TLB的大小。
Another way to increase the performance
另一种提高性能的方法是什么？
in what you learn, we learned in the past,
在你所学的东西中，我们在过去也学过。
is to increase the cache size.
是增加缓存大小。
In order to reduce, to also improve the performance,
为了减少，同时也提高性能，
system performance, program performance,
系统性能，程序性能
you can also increase the memory size.
你还可以增加内存大小。
Of course, there is a Belladia anomaly,
当然，存在着贝拉迪亚异常。
which as you know, for certain page replacement policies,
正如你所知，对于某些页面置换策略来说，
increasing the size of the memory,
增加内存的大小
or the size of the cache,
或者缓存的大小，
doesn't necessarily reduce the number of false, page faults.
并不一定减少虚假的页面错误数量。
But in general, for many of those page replacement policy,
但总的来说，对于许多页面置换策略来说，
like ALERU, that's increasing the memory size,
像ALERU这样，它增加了内存大小。
always will likely decrease,
总是会有可能减少。
most likely will decrease the number of page faults.
最有可能会减少页面错误的数量。
These are a few examples where you can have
这是一些你可以拥有的例子。
increase the number of the space,
增加空间的数量
to increase the space and to improve the speed.
增加空间并提高速度。
And other techniques are reduce the overheads
其他技术是减少开销。
through user level drivers.
通过用户级驱动程序。
So basically, if you can implement the functionality
所以基本上，如果你能够实现这个功能
as a user level, you may avoid the context switching,
作为用户级别，您可以避免上下文切换。
because you don't need the operating system
因为你不需要操作系统
in order to handle these requests.
为了处理这些请求。
And the other one is like I mentioned earlier, the overlap.
另一个就是我之前提到的，重叠部分。
So while you are waiting for an I/O to complete,
所以当你在等待I/O完成时，
you are doing the useful, more useful work.
你正在做一项有用、更有用的工作。
And this can happen at multiple, in multiple levels.
这可以发生在多个层面上。
It can happen in your, the operating system,
这可能发生在你的操作系统中，
as you now, when operating system on a thread
正如你所知，当操作系统在一个线程上运行时
is blocked on an I/O device, on an I/O request,
被阻塞在一个I/O设备上，在一个I/O请求上，
is going to switch it out,
将要更换它，
it putting the thread on the waiting queue,
将线程放入等待队列中，
and is going to schedule, the operating system
并且将要安排，操作系统
is going to schedule a new thread,
将安排一个新的线程。
which is on the ready queue.
在就绪队列中。
Okay, so now we're going to look into a bit
好的，现在我们要稍微深入一点。
into the disk scheduling, right?
进入磁盘调度，对吗？
The disk remember is quite complicated, right?
磁盘记忆是相当复杂的，对吗？
You has multiple plates,
你有多个盘子。
and each plate has two surfaces, up, down,
每个盘子都有两个表面，上面和下面。
and then you have cylinders and sectors, right?
然后你有圆柱体和扇区，对吗？
So when a request comes in from the operating system
当操作系统收到一个请求时
to read or write on the disk,
读取或写入磁盘，
is going to tell you, typically is telling you
会告诉你，通常正在告诉你。
what is a cylinder, the face, the surface,
什么是圆柱体，面，表面？
and what is the sector, right?
行业是什么，对吗？
Here we are talking, we are considering a simpler example
这里我们正在交谈，我们正在考虑一个更简单的例子。
where you have the, just the cylinder and the sector.
你只需要一个圆柱体和一个扇形。
And this is, this is how the request look like.
这是，这是请求的样子。
So in this case, you have two numbers,
所以在这种情况下，你有两个数字，
for each request, a cylinder and the sector.
每个请求都包括一个柱面和扇区。
The request also is going to specify
请求还将具体说明。
what is the read and write.
读和写是指从存储设备中读取数据或向存储设备中写入数据的操作。
And because this disk is slow,
而且由于这个硬盘速度慢，
more likely you are going to have some requests
更有可能的是，你将会有一些请求。
which are queued, okay?
哪些是排队的，好吗？
So now the interesting aspect here,
所以现在这里的有趣之处是，
the requests are in general are independent,
请求通常是独立的。
are in general independent.
一般来说是独立的。
So now the question is how you are going
现在的问题是你现在过得如何。
to serve these requests.
为了满足这些请求。
A simplest way is five, right?
最简单的方法是五，对吗？
You serve the request in the order in which they arrived.
您按照请求到达的顺序进行服务。
This is fair among the requester,
这是请求者之间的公平。
that is fair with respect to the order
这个订单是公平的。
in which they submit the request.
在他们提交请求的地方。
But it can be very long six.
但是六个可以非常长。
Why?
为什么？
Because the head can go, you know, randomly from, you know,
因为头部可以随机地，你知道的，从，你知道的地方转动。
from one cylinder or one track to another, right?
是的，从一个气缸或一个轨道到另一个，对吗？
You don't run that because you remember
你不运行那个是因为你记得
the seek time is very expensive, right?
寻找时间很昂贵，对吗？
As well as, you know, rotation latency.
还有，你知道的，旋转延迟。
So you don't want to go, you know,
所以你不想去，你知道的，
you want to be smarter than that.
你想变得比那更聪明。
So that'll be a smart way to do it, right?
那样做是个聪明的方式，对吗？
If you want to minimize the seek time,
如果你想要最小化寻道时间，
once you serve a request and you are in a certain position
一旦你接受了一个请求并处于某个特定的位置
on the disk, you look, you want to look in the queue
在磁盘上，你看，你想要查看队列中的内容。
and take the request which is closest to you,
并接受离你最近的请求。
because if the request is closest to you,
因为如果请求离你最近，
you are going to minimize the seek time.
你将要最小化寻道时间。
And this is shorter seek time first, right?
这是更短的寻道时间优先，对吗？
You pick the request that it closes to the head on the disk.
你选择最接近磁盘头部的请求。
Okay?
好的。
Of course, in general,
当然，在一般情况下，
you also need to include the rotation delay,
你还需要包括旋转延迟。
not only the seek time,
不仅仅是寻找时间，
but for now let's simplify it only to seek time.
但现在让我们简化它，只关注寻找时间。
Okay?
好的。
So now the seek will reduce the time if you look,
所以现在如果你寻找，时间会减少。
but it's not good.
但这不好。
What is not good is that may lead to starvation.
不好的是可能会导致饥饿。
Like for instance,
比如说，
if a lot of requests come and they are clustered close by,
如果有很多请求并且它们靠得很近，
then according to these disciplines,
那么根据这些学科，
you are shorter seek time first,
你首先要寻找短的寻找时间。
you are going to serve this request.
你将会处理这个请求。
And the request which is farther,
而且那个请求更远一些，
a lot, you know, which is farther,
很多，你知道的，哪个更远，
like for instance, at the edge on the disk,
例如，在磁盘的边缘，
may wait for a long time to be serviced.
可能需要等很长时间才能得到服务。
Make sense?
有意义吗？
So you don't want that.
所以你不想要那个。
Again, the rate of a seek time, but it's unfair.
再次，寻道时间的速率，但这是不公平的。
Can cause starvation.
可能导致饥饿。
So one solution to that is scan.
所以解决方案之一是扫描。
It's a pretty nice solution.
这是一个相当不错的解决方案。
These are what you see here, these numbers.
这些是你在这里看到的，这些数字。
Think about these are tracks or cylinders, right?
想一想这些是磁道还是柱面，对吗？
A cylinder, it's all the tracks
一个圆柱体，它是所有轨道。
which are under the heads on different platters.
这些位于不同盘片上的磁头。
So scan is basically you start going into one direction,
所以扫描基本上是你开始朝一个方向前进，
either to the edge of the disk or to the inside of the disk.
要么到磁盘的边缘，要么到磁盘的内部。
And you are only going to serve the request
你只需要处理这个请求。
in the direction you are going, right?
你是指你所走的方向，对吗？
So you serve the request on say track 53,
所以你会处理第53轨道上的请求，
then you look in the queue and you have multiple requests.
然后你查看队列，发现有多个请求。
Say you pick the one which is closest to you
选择离你最近的那个。
in the direction you are going, it's 37.
你所走的方向是37。
Then the next one is 14 and so forth.
然后下一个是14，依此类推。
And in this time, so for instance,
而在这个时候，例如，
if when you serve the request 53, you get the request 65,
如果在处理请求53时，你收到了请求65，
this is closest to you.
这是离你最近的地方。
So according to the shorter six time first,
根据较短的六次先，
you'll serve this request.
你会处理这个请求。
Because it's not in the request on track 65,
因为在第65页的请求中没有提到。
it's not in the direction of your movement,
这不是你移动的方向。
you are going to ignore it, right?
你打算忽略它，对吗？
So you go until the last request in your direction
所以你一直走到最后一个请求在你的方向上。
and then after you reverse.
然后再反过来。
So here I say no starvation,
所以我在这里说没有饥饿，
but still retain a flavor of shortest six time first.
但仍然保留了最短六次首次的风味。
Why is that?
为什么这样呢？
Tell me, why is that?
告诉我，为什么会这样？
Why do we still have a problem with this one, with scan?
为什么我们在这个问题上仍然有困扰，与扫描有关？
By the way, it's also, it's called elevator algorithm.
顺便说一下，它也被称为电梯算法。
Can you think about, does scan exhibit any unfairness?
你能思考一下，扫描是否展示了任何不公平的行为吗？
And why, if yes.
为什么，如果是的话。
(silence)
对不起，我无法翻译空白的内容。请提供需要翻译的具体文本。
Yes, I just want to say you may never reverse
是的，我只是想说你可能永远无法逆转。
if tasks keep arriving at the same spot.
如果任务持续到达同一位置。
So basically on the same track, that's true.
所以基本上是在同一个轨道上，没错。
That's a pretty edge case.
这是一个相当特殊的情况。
It's a good answer, but it's a little bit edge.
这是一个很好的答案，但有点边缘。
What else?
还有什么？
Can you think about some other requests
你能考虑一些其他的请求吗？
which will get preferential treatment
哪一个会得到优先处理
if they are in some region of the disk versus others?
如果它们在磁盘的某个区域与其他区域有所不同？
(silence)
对不起，我没有听到你说话。你能再重复一遍吗？
Oh, Karl asked a question.
哦，Karl问了一个问题。
How do we define the initial direction for scan?
我们如何定义扫描的初始方向？
I guess, I mean, it's a good question.
我猜，我的意思是，这是一个好问题。
I don't know, but I don't think it matters.
我不知道，但我觉得这并不重要。
You can choose anyone initially.
你可以最初选择任何人。
Yeah.
是的。
There is more data on the outer rings.
外环上有更多的数据。
So traveling is disfavored.
所以旅行不受欢迎。
Yeah, you are right.
是的，你说得对。
It's like, let me see, it's also a question here.
这个问题嘛，让我想想，这里也有一个问题。
Okay, it's the same question.
好的，这是同一个问题。
So Karl, it's again, the answer to your question,
所以卡尔，这又是对你问题的回答，
how do you define the initial directions?
你如何定义初始方向？
I think it doesn't matter.
我认为这没关系。
You can, but I do not know,
你可以，但是我不知道。
and I don't see a reason that's very important.
我不认为有一个非常重要的原因。
And going back now,
回到现在，
it is going back about when this scan is not fair.
这个扫描不公平的问题是什么时候开始的？
So here, when it's not fair,
所以在这里，当不公平的时候，
which requests are fair,
哪些请求是公平的？
for which requests does scan provide advantage, favor them?
Scan provides advantages for requests that require scanning or analyzing information. It is particularly beneficial for requests that involve data processing, data extraction, or data interpretation.
So here, the request in the middle,
所以在这里，中间的请求是什么？
you get quicker to the request in the middle,
你在中间的请求上更快地得到了回应。
right?
对吗？
Like for instance, I can go to a request,
比如，我可以去处理一个请求，
say it takes one millisecond to go from one end to another.
说从一端到另一端需要一毫秒的时间。
If I missed a request arrives here,
如果我错过了一个请求到达这里，
just after the scan has passed in that direction,
刚刚在那个方向上扫描过之后，
just I missed it.
我刚刚错过了。
So I say, okay, it goes 0.5 milliseconds to one end,
所以我说，好吧，它需要0.5毫秒到达一端，
and I wait for another 0.5 milliseconds
我等待另外0.5毫秒。
to come to me back.
回到我身边。
So I wait for one millisecond.
所以我等待一毫秒。
But if this happens when I'm at the edge,
但是如果这发生在我处于边缘的时候，
so I just missed the head,
所以我刚刚错过了机会。
which now goes towards the inside of the disk.
现在朝向磁盘内部。
Then you have to wait for two milliseconds.
那你需要等待两毫秒。
You need to wait one millisecond
你需要等待一毫秒。
to go all the way to the inside,
走到最里面，
and one millisecond to go back.
并且需要一毫秒返回。
Okay, now I'm oversimplifying things here,
好的，现在我在这里过于简化事情，
but just to give you a sense.
但只是为了让你有个概念。
So scan favors the requests which are in the middle,
所以扫描偏向于处理那些位于中间的请求。
right?
对吗？
And not the request which are at the edges.
而不是边缘上的请求。
What is the solution here?
这里有什么解决方案？
Well, the solution is circular scan or C-scan.
好的，解决方案是循环扫描或C扫描。
And this basically just go one direction.
这基本上只是朝一个方向前进。
So say you go all the way to the,
那么假设你一直走到了...
you send the request only in one direction.
你只发送了单向请求。
And when you are done with those,
然后当你完成这些之后，
you immediately go to all the other edge
你立即去到所有其他的边缘。
and start serving them again.
并重新开始为他们提供服务。
Okay?
好的。
So that's kind of what it is.
那就是大致的情况。
But I'll say if I missed, if I request,
但是我要说，如果我错过了，如果我请求的话，
I just misses the head,
我刚刚错过了目标。
no matter what the request is,
无论请求是什么，
on the average is going to wait for the same time
平均而言，将会等待相同的时间。
for the head to come to be back to be served.
头部回来被服务。
Okay?
好的。
This is not biased towards the pages in the middle.
这不偏向于中间的页面。
Finally, I mentioned that you can hide the latency.
最后，我提到你可以隐藏延迟。
How do you hide the IO latency?
你如何隐藏IO延迟？
If the blocking interface is a wait, we already discussed,
如果阻塞接口是一个等待，我们已经讨论过了。
you have a block read and write system call,
你有一个块读写系统调用。
you put process operating system,
你提到了进程操作系统。
put processes to sleep until the data is ready,
将进程置于休眠状态，直到数据准备就绪。
the request is served.
请求已处理。
And during this time, the operating system schedules tasks,
而在此期间，操作系统会安排任务，
ready tasks, which can use a CPU.
准备好的任务，可以使用CPU。
Non-blocking interfaces don't wait.
非阻塞接口不会等待。
So basically this, you remember,
所以基本上就是这样，你记得吧，
this is the interface in which you are just going
这是你刚刚进入的界面。
to issue the request, but then returns immediately.
发出请求，但立即返回。
You just, after you return, you do something else.
你回来后，你可以做其他事情。
Right?
对吗？
And then later you need to go
然后之后你需要去。
and see whether you got the data.
并查看你是否获得了数据。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
Or you wrote the data to the kernel.
或者你将数据写入了内核。
And asynchronous interface is then later,
然后是一个异步接口。
again, it's like in the non-blocking interface,
再次，就像在非阻塞接口中一样，
it returns immediately the request,
它立即返回请求，
because in this case, for instance,
因为在这种情况下，例如，
when you get the data, you allocate the buffer,
当你获取到数据时，你分配缓冲区。
you give the pointer as a buffer,
你将指针作为缓冲区。
and tells the operating system basically,
并且基本上告诉操作系统，
put the data when available,
请在数据可用时放置。
starting from this pointer, right in the buffer.
从这个指针开始，在缓冲区中。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
And then let me know.
然后告诉我。
And when you send the data, it's the same, right?
当你发送数据时，是一样的，对吗？
You are going to create a buffer,
你将要创建一个缓冲区。
you are going there, you are going to,
你要去那里，你要去。
you know, where you put the data,
你知道，你把数据放在哪里。
where you want to send,
你想要发送到哪里？
and then you give to the kernel, to the OS,
然后你将其交给内核，交给操作系统，
in the right operation, in the right system call,
在正确的操作中，在正确的系统调用中，
you give the pointer of the buffer
你提供了缓冲区的指针。
you want to be transferred.
你想要调岗。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
So now recall the entire error here for the IO.
所以现在回顾一下这里的整个IO错误。
This is a top part, which provides the API
这是一个顶部部分，提供API。
and the abstraction to the applications,
以及对应用程序的抽象化处理，
whether it's streams or it's a block API,
无论是流还是块API，
plus the system calls open, read, write, and close.
加上系统调用open、read、write和close。
Then at the bottom, we also covered last time,
然后在底部，我们也上次讨论过，
this is about IO drivers, controllers, right?
这是关于IO驱动程序和控制器的，对吗？
These are the drivers which are interacting
这些是正在交互的驱动程序。
with the physical device,
使用物理设备，
read and write the data to the physical device.
读取并将数据写入物理设备。
And the middle is a system which kind of
而中间是一种什么样的系统？
makes a conversion in some sense
在某种意义上进行转换
from the API, which is provided to the application
从API中，这个API是提供给应用程序的。
by the operating system and the API of the IO driver,
通过操作系统和IO驱动的API，
which is a block interface in general.
一般情况下，这是一个块接口。
Right?
对吗？
So more precisely for the API,
所以更准确地说，针对API来说，
for the higher level for the application,
对于应用的高级别，
you typically have a variable size buffer.
你通常会有一个可变大小的缓冲区。
And for the file system,
文件系统方面，
which you are going to talk more about this,
你将要更多地谈论这个。
you are going to have blocks,
你将会有一些障碍。
but the blocks are logically indexed.
但是这些块是按逻辑顺序编制索引的。
These are where the data is stored, right?
这些是数据存储的地方，对吗？
Logically indexed means that the index
逻辑索引的意思是索引
in the operating system is not the same index,
在操作系统中索引不同。
which of that block on the physical device.
这个物理设备上的哪个块？
This is done by the hardware device
这是由硬件设备完成的。
and by their controllers mapping from this block device,
并通过它们的控制器从这个块设备进行映射，
from the operating system to the blocks
从操作系统到块
or the sectors on the hard disk drives.
或者硬盘驱动器上的扇区。
Remember that the blocks in the operating system
请记住操作系统中的块。
are typically have like 24 kilobytes
通常有大约24千字节。
and sectors on the hard disk drives are smaller.
硬盘驱动器上的扇区更小。
They are 512 bytes.
它们是512字节。
So you have typically, you can have eight sectors for each
所以通常情况下，每个部门可以有八个部门。
or a block requires eight sectors.
或者一个块需要八个扇区。
And you have an SSD,
你有一块固态硬盘，
you remember you have these flash translation layers,
你记得你有这些闪存翻译层，
which again maps the logical index of the blocks
再次映射块的逻辑索引。
to the physical blocks.
到物理块。
That's pretty much what you have.
这基本上就是你所拥有的。
And also you have your agent pages.
并且你还有你的代理商页面。
So let's look now,
那么现在让我们来看一下，
we are going to start looking more,
我们打算开始更多地寻找，
a little bit more depths to the file system.
文件系统需要更深入一点。
And one way to define it, like I mentioned,
而且，就像我之前提到的，有一种定义方法，
it's a layer of the operating system
这是操作系统的一层。
that maps the API provided to the application,
将提供的API映射到应用程序的功能。
which is files, directories, stream of bytes
其中包括文件、目录和字节流。
into lower level API of the IO devices,
进入IO设备的低级API
which is a block interface.
这是一个块接口。
Right.
好的。
[Silence]
[沉默]
And there are a few things, you know, this needs to be done, the operating system.
还有一些事情，你知道的，这需要做，操作系统。
And that's naming.
这就是命名。
You need to find file by name, you don't give to the OS a block where the data is.
你需要通过文件名来查找文件，而不是给操作系统一个数据所在的块。
You let operating system worry about mapping between the file name and the block.
你让操作系统来处理文件名和块之间的映射。
And this is part of the organization.
这是组织的一部分。
Also part of the organization is about the file names are typically within directories.
组织的一部分还涉及文件名通常位于目录中。
So you need also to locate the file name within a particular directory.
所以你还需要在特定目录中定位文件名。
Also need to provide protection.
还需要提供保护。
We enforce access restriction.
我们执行访问限制。
When do you do that?
你什么时候做那个？
When you open the file typically.
当你通常打开文件时。
And those finally reliability.
而那些最终的可靠性。
Why do you store the data on the disk?
为什么你把数据存储在磁盘上？
Because it's durable.
因为它耐用。
You want to survive data to survive when there are crashes or when your laptop is powered
当发生崩溃或您的笔记本电脑断电时，您希望将数据保存下来以确保存活。
out.
出去。
So from the user perspective, then I have some data structures which I want to store
所以从用户的角度来看，我有一些数据结构需要存储。
those data structure view.
这些数据结构视图。
That's what I want as a user.
这就是我作为用户想要的。
And that was a file system should offer me.
那是一个文件系统应该提供给我的。
Now from the system view, and I'm talking here about the call interface, the API as
现在从系统的角度来看，我在这里谈论的是呼叫接口，也就是API。
a boundary between the operating system and the user space.
操作系统和用户空间之间的边界。
It doesn't have any idea about what data structure the application has.
它对应用程序的数据结构一无所知。
It just see a bunch of bytes, a collection of bytes.
它只是一串字节，一组字节。
So the system needs to take this collection of bytes, this bunch of bytes, and write them
所以系统需要将这一串字节，这一堆字节，写入。
on the device hard disk drive.
在设备的硬盘驱动器上。
Then the system view that it's inside the kernel.
然后系统视图认为它在内核内部。
This is the one which interfaces to the devices.
这是与设备进行接口的那个。
It takes a collection of block and it sees a collection of bytes and maps them to a collection
它接收一个块的集合，并将其视为一组字节，并将其映射到一个集合。
of blocks.
的区块。
The collection of blocks are still logically identified.
这些区块的集合仍然在逻辑上被识别。
Logically again means that these are their identification.
逻辑上来说，这些是他们的身份证明。
It's not the physical identification or these blocks are on the disk.
这不是物理识别或者这些块在磁盘上。
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
And like I mentioned, the block size is typically greater than sector size.
而且正如我之前提到的，块大小通常大于扇区大小。
So let's see what happens when, for instance, the user says to the operating system, I want
那么让我们看看当用户对操作系统说，比如说，我想要的时候会发生什么。
bytes between two and twelve from this file.
从这个文件中提取两个和十二个之间的字节。
Well, the operating system has to face a block corresponding to those bytes and just return
好的，操作系统必须面对与这些字节对应的阻塞，并且只需返回。
the correct portion to the operating system, to the application.
正确的部分是指向操作系统的，也是指向应用程序的。
What about when you write bytes between two and twelve?
当你写入两到十二之间的字节时怎么办？
You fetch the block from the disk, you modify the relevant portion and you write down the
你从磁盘中读取块，修改相关部分，然后写入。
block, back the block.
阻止，回到原位。
So for writing these 10 bytes, you get the block.
所以为了写入这10个字节，你会得到一个块。
Which is four kilobytes.
四千字节。
Update these 10 bytes and then write back the four kilobytes.
更新这10个字节，然后将四千字节写回。
So everything between the operating system and the devices is a block ground-large.
所以操作系统和设备之间的一切都是一个大的块接地。
So therefore, you always are going to pay the overhead of reading and writing blocks
所以，你总是要承担读写块的开销。
as a block ground-large.
作为一个大型的街区地面。
OK, so it's again a file system.
好的，所以这又是一个文件系统。
You have directories and files.
你有目录和文件。
Directory, you can think about that user visible index mapping names to files.
目录，你可以把它看作是用户可见的将名称映射到文件的索引。
And the disk is just a linear array of sectors.
而且磁盘只是一个线性的扇区数组。
You can look at it.
你可以看一下。
It's a sector on you have a bunch of sectors on a track and you have a bunch of tracks
这是一个关于轨道和扇区的部分，你在一个轨道上有一堆扇区，而且你有一堆轨道。
on a face of a platter.
在一个盘子的表面上。
And then for each platter, you have two faces and then for a hard disk drive, you have multiple
然后对于每个盘片，你有两个面，而对于硬盘驱动器，你有多个。
multiple platters.
多个盘片。
So therefore, a sector is defined by, like I mentioned earlier on, by the cylinder, the
因此，一个扇区的定义是，正如我之前提到的那样，由圆柱体所确定的，
surface and the sector.
表面和扇形。
Now the main point to take from this slide and it's reemphasizing what I said earlier
现在从这张幻灯片中要得出的主要观点是，它再次强调了我之前所说的。
on, is that the operating system doesn't track at the level the sector using their physical
对，操作系统并不在物理层面追踪扇区的使用情况。
identifier.
标识符。
The physical identifier again here is a cylinder, surface and sector on the disk.
物理标识符在这里是指磁盘上的柱面、表面和扇区。
Instead you have a logical block addressing and typically now the controller translates
相反，您拥有逻辑块寻址，并且通常现在控制器进行翻译。
this logical block addressing to the physical block address.
这个逻辑块地址对应着物理块地址。
It's something similar with virtual addresses.
这与虚拟地址类似。
The way that the operating system is responsible for translating the virtual addresses to the
操作系统负责将虚拟地址转换为物理地址的方式
physical addresses.
物理地址。
Let me answer this question from Alison.
让我回答一下Alison的问题。
Why don't we build devices that let us do lower, basically, I guess lower granularity
为什么我们不制造一些设备，让我们能够进行更低层次的操作，基本上，我猜就是更低的粒度。
of reads and writes?
读和写的数量？
I guess, you know, this is a very good question.
我猜，你知道，这是一个非常好的问题。
And the answer is the overhead.
答案是开销。
So you are correct.
所以你是正确的。
Alison, this is because efficiency.
艾莉森，这是因为效率。
Remember again, just think about the hard disk drives.
再次记住，只需考虑硬盘驱动器。
If you remember the hard disk drives in the last lecture, there is some example.
如果你还记得上一堂课中的硬盘驱动器，这里有一些例子。
The seek and rotation latency were like eight, nine milliseconds.
寻道时间和旋转延迟大约为八、九毫秒。
And the time to transfer a block, even if the block as a sector, even if the sector
而且即使是将一个块作为一个扇区进行传输，传输所需的时间也是相同的。
is 500 terabytes, it's not only one byte, was much less than one millisecond.
500 terabytes相当于500万兆字节，远远超过了一个字节，而且远远少于一毫秒的时间。
So the time to transfer to random the access and transfer a sector is dwarfed by the rotation
因此，将数据传输到随机访问并传输一个扇区的时间被磁盘的旋转时间所远远超过。
latency, by the fixed overhead, rotation latency and seek back.
延迟，由固定开销、旋转延迟和寻道回退所引起。
So is that because there is always an overhead?
所以这是因为总会有额外开销吗？
Another way to think about is here it is another way to think about and maybe let me just connect
另一种思考方式是这样的，这是另一种思考方式，也许让我来连接一下。
the dots here.
这里有点。
Remember this slide?
记得这张幻灯片吗？
Look here at this formula.
请看这个公式。
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
The smaller the B is, the less the effective bandwidth is.
B越小，有效带宽就越小。
If B is very small, S will dominate the fixed overhead.
如果B非常小，S将主导固定开销。
This is just overhead.
这只是额外的开销。
It's useless work.
这是无用的工作。
And the smaller the B is, the lower the effective bandwidth is.
而且B越小，有效带宽就越低。
Look at the red curve here.
看这里的红色曲线。
So that's what you have.
那就是你所拥有的。
Each request, processing each request has a fixed overhead.
每个请求，处理每个请求都有固定的开销。
Even if this is on, let me go here, even if this device is solid, it's SSD, not disk drive.
即使这个打开了，让我去这里，即使这个设备很坚固，它是固态硬盘，不是磁盘驱动器。
There is an overhead for controller.
控制器有一定的开销。
Is there an overhead for context switching and things like that?
上下文切换和类似的操作会有额外开销吗？
OK, hopefully I answered your question.
好的，希望我回答了你的问题。
OK, let's go back.
好的，让我们回去吧。
So what do you need for file system needs?
那么，你对文件系统有什么需求？
What do you know if you design a file system?
如果你设计一个文件系统，你需要了解什么？
What do you need to be careful about?
你需要注意什么？
You need basically to track which for a file, which are the blocks containing the data from
你基本上需要追踪一个文件中包含数据的块。
that file.
那个文件。
You need to track it.
你需要追踪它。
You need to for a particular file, you need to know which directory contains it.
你需要查找一个特定的文件，你需要知道它所在的目录。
And then you need to track the free disk blocks, because if you write something new in a file,
然后你需要跟踪空闲的磁盘块，因为如果你在文件中写入新内容，
you need to know which blocks are free, are empty.
你需要知道哪些块是空闲的，是空的。
And then you also need to decide how to maintain this information.
然后你还需要决定如何维护这些信息。
The answer is the information has to be persistent.
答案是信息必须是持久的。
So because it's persistent, you have to maintain it on the disk.
所以由于它是持久的，你必须将它保存在磁盘上。
So it's again, data structures on the disk is different from the data structure in memory.
所以，再说一遍，磁盘上的数据结构与内存中的数据结构是不同的。
The application, you have a data structure.
这个应用程序中有一个数据结构。
The disk or even the operating system is unaware, completely oblivious about the data structure
磁盘甚至操作系统对于数据结构毫无察觉，完全无知。
you have in your program.
你的程序中有什么功能？
It just sees a bunch of bytes and later a bunch of blocks.
它只是看到一串字节，然后是一堆块。
That's what it is.
就是这样。
Again, because you access a block at a time, it's not very, these things, accesses are
再次，由于您一次只能访问一个块，所以这些东西，访问起来并不是很方便。
not very efficient for when you access just a byte.
当你只访问一个字节时，效率不是很高。
And obviously, like I mentioned, when you write to a disk, you expect to be durable.
显然，正如我之前提到的，当你将数据写入磁盘时，你希望它是持久的。
That's why you write to a disk, otherwise you keep the things in memory.
这就是为什么你要将东西写入磁盘，否则它们会保留在内存中。
But here you need to be careful.
但是在这里你需要小心。
You cannot assume that if you write to a disk, if you say, I call the write operation, everything
你不能假设如果你向磁盘写入数据，就像你说的，调用写入操作，一切都会成功。
is fine.
好的。
Why is that?
为什么呢？
Tell me why if I just call the write operation to a file, I cannot be completely sure that
告诉我为什么如果我只调用文件的写操作，我不能完全确定...
this, the data I wrote has been stored durably on the disk.
这个，我写的数据已经被持久地存储在硬盘上了。
Yes.
是的。
If you remember, we discussed early on about buffer cache.
如果你还记得的话，我们之前讨论过缓冲区缓存。
So the data is not stored directly on the disk, it's stored in a buffer.
所以数据并不直接存储在磁盘上，而是存储在缓冲区中。
So if after you submit the request, the application fails, the operating system fails, the data
所以，如果您提交请求后，应用程序失败，操作系统失败，数据丢失。
may be lost.
可能会迷失。
You need to call.
你需要打电话。
You need to call in order to make sure the data goes to the disk.
你需要打电话确认数据已经写入磁盘。
What system call you are going to invoke?
你打算调用哪个系统调用？
Flash.
闪光。
Very good.
非常好。
Although I would wish also to have more people answering these questions.
虽然我也希望有更多的人回答这些问题。
So it's again, it's not a wrong answer.
所以，这又不是一个错误的答案。
It's about discussing it and you'll remember much easier if we have this kind of discussions
这是关于讨论的，如果我们进行这种讨论，你会更容易记住。
rather than me just talking and talking and talking and being boring.
与其我一直在说个不停，让人觉得无聊，不如...
So OK.
所以好吧。
A few announcements, you know very well tomorrow, this is 11.3.
一些公告，你很清楚明天是11月3日。
Let me just find.
让我找一下。
Tomorrow we have the exam.
明天我们有考试。
I wish you the best of luck.
祝你好运。
All the materials is up to and included the last lecture, not this lecture.
所有的材料都包括最后一次讲座，而不是这次讲座。
And the project deadline, it was pushed.
项目的截止日期被推迟了。
So now you have a little bit more time.
所以现在你有更多的时间了。
So hopefully this really helps you.
希望这真的对你有所帮助。
OK.
Sure. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
Again, let's go even deeper talking about the file system.
再次，让我们更深入地讨论文件系统。
So again, a few core elements.
所以，再次强调几个核心要素。
The file system design, if you are talking about the performance, the dominant factor,
文件系统的设计，如果你在谈论性能的话，主导因素是什么？
you are talking about this bottleneck, the bottleneck is a disk performance.
你在谈论这个瓶颈，这个瓶颈是磁盘性能。
The disk works better, provides the best performance when we sequentially read and write data because
磁盘在顺序读写数据时表现更好，提供最佳性能，因为
we avoid seek times and rotation latencies.
我们避免寻道时间和旋转延迟。
So you want to maximize these operations.
所以你想要最大化这些操作。
Remember we can, it's a file system abstraction provided in Unix.
记住我们可以，它是Unix提供的一个文件系统抽象。
You need to, it's open, close and in between you read write.
你需要的是，它是开放的，关闭的，以及在其中你读写。
You cannot read and write to a disk without the file system, without the file, without
没有文件系统，没有文件，你就无法读写磁盘。
opening and closing that file.
打开和关闭那个文件。
The cool thing about this is that you can perform the protection checks, admission control.
这个很酷的地方是你可以执行保护检查、准入控制。
And all at the open, when you open the file, otherwise you would have to check for protection
并且全部都是公开的，当你打开文件时，否则你将需要检查保护措施。
every time you access that file.
每次你访问那个文件。
The size of the file is variable.
文件的大小是可变的。
When you start writing, you start with one block.
当你开始写作时，你从一个块开始。
We need more than one sector.
我们需要不止一个部门。
We need more.
我们需要更多。
You are going, the file system is going to allocate more.
你要去了，文件系统将会分配更多空间。
So you don't need to predefine.
所以你不需要预先定义。
This is very important.
这非常重要。
You take it as a giver.
你把它当作一个给予者。
But it's not.
但它不是。
Another design is like you would just allocate space on the disk and before you start writing.
另一种设计是在开始写入之前，只需在磁盘上分配空间。
And why is that natural?
这是为什么自然的呢？
It can be natural because how do you do it in your favorite programming language like
这可能是自然的，因为你可以用你喜欢的编程语言来实现它。
C, right?
是的，C对吗？
How do you manipulate the memory?
你如何操作内存？
How do you manipulate the storage of memory?
你如何操作存储器的存储？
Before you read or before you write some data, what do you need to do?
在你阅读或写入数据之前，你需要做什么？
You need to allocate memory.
你需要分配内存。
Malloc or Calloc.
分配内存空间时，可以使用Malloc或Calloc。
When allocating memory, you can use Malloc or Calloc.
So you allocate first and then write.
所以你先分配，然后再写入。
Here is not needed.
这里不需要。
You just write and the operating system and the file system in particular will take care
你只需要写作，特别是操作系统和文件系统会处理好的。
of growing the size of the file as needed.
根据需要增加文件的大小。
The files are organized in directory.
这些文件被组织在目录中。
You have a directory structure and this directory structure, the directory is a file.
你有一个目录结构，而在这个目录结构中，目录也是一种文件。
It's also stored on the disk.
它也存储在磁盘上。
And then you need to allocate.
然后你需要分配。
When you allocate, I think we are going to see that in the next lecture.
当你分配时，我认为我们将在下一堂课上看到这一点。
When we allocate more sectors on the disk, you want to allocate them contiguously.
当我们在磁盘上分配更多的扇区时，你希望将它们连续分配。
Why is that?
为什么呢？
Because when you read the data, if the data was written on a bunch of sectors, which is
因为当你读取数据时，如果数据是写在一堆扇区上的，这就是
contiguous, you maximize the sequential accesses, right?
连续的，你是在最大化顺序访问，对吗？
Sequential reads in this case, which improves the performance.
在这种情况下，进行顺序读取可以提高性能。
So here how things look like under the hood a little bit.
所以这里是一些底层的情况。
On one end, I have the file path, which is the file path is a name of the file prefixed
在一端，我有文件路径，文件路径是文件名的前缀。
by the directory path name where the file is residing in each directory path.
通过文件所在的目录路径名称来确定。
At the other end, you have data blocks which are stored on the disk in sectors.
在另一端，你有存储在磁盘上的数据块，它们以扇区的形式存储。
So you need somehow to map from the file path to the data blocks.
所以你需要找到一种方法，将文件路径映射到数据块。
And this is what the operating system file system is wrong.
这是操作系统文件系统出现的问题。
Right?
对吗？
You take the file path, which is going to point some in some directory structure.
你需要提供文件路径，该路径将指向某个目录结构中的某个位置。
You are going to find the file and the file is going to be as you are going to identify
你将要找到这个文件，而这个文件将会如你所确定的那样。
by a number.
通过一个数字。
It's called I number.
它被称为I号码。
And this I number is going to point to a data structure, which is called I node, which contains
而这个数字将指向一个数据结构，称为I节点，其中包含
all the information about that file, like for permissions, protection permissions.
关于该文件的所有信息，例如权限、保护权限等。
And also information about the blocks or the data in the file is stored.
还有关于块或文件中数据的信息被存储。
This is the I node.
这是I节点。
OK, here is another view.
好的，这里是另一个观点。
You remember about this.
你还记得这件事吗？
We had many lectures ago.
我们之前有很多讲座。
This is a view from the process perspective.
这是一个从过程角度来看的观点。
So here you have a process, you have threads, registers, and you have the address space.
所以在这里你有一个进程，你有线程，寄存器，还有地址空间。
And then when you open a file, you get a file descriptors.
然后当你打开一个文件时，你会得到一个文件描述符。
The file descriptors points to a data structure here, which is in the operating system.
文件描述符指向这里的一个数据结构，该数据结构位于操作系统中。
It's really at the end of the day, you are going to have the I node.
这句话的意思是"说到底，你最终会拥有I节点。"
But anyway, the file description here, you know, in this case, you have a file name.
但无论如何，在这里的文件描述中，你知道，在这种情况下，你有一个文件名。
And you have position, what's the position in the file?
您的位置是什么？在文件中的位置是什么？
What is the position you are going to read and write?
你打算读和写的职位是什么？
from. Right? And then you are going, this is going to read from file descriptor 3 and
是的。然后你要做的是从文件描述符3中读取。
into this buffer and you are going to copy the data from position 100 in the file. So
将数据复制到这个缓冲区中，并且你将从文件的第100个位置开始复制。所以
from position 100 of file identified by descriptor 3 read data into this buffer. But really the
从由描述符3标识的文件的第100个位置读取数据到该缓冲区。但实际上，
way you need to think about this, that instead of this file, you are going to have inumber.
你需要考虑的方式是，不再使用这个文件，而是使用一个编号。
Like I mentioned from here, you just need to point directly to this and inumber points
就像我在这里提到的那样，你只需要直接指向这个地方，并且列出数字点。
to an inode. But let me tell you, let me ask you this question. Why do you think instead
将其转换为inode。但是让我告诉你，让我问你一个问题。你为什么认为这样做更好呢？
of food or text here, I should just keep the inumber. Right? Which is how an identifier
在这里，我应该只保留数字，对吗？这是一个标识符的方式。
by the operating system of that particular file. Why inumber and not food text? Let me
通过那个特定文件的操作系统。为什么是i节点号而不是文件文本？让我来翻译一下。
help you a little bit. Look at this picture. While I number and not file or text. I don't
能帮你一点点。看这张图片。虽然有数字，但没有文件或文本。我不明白你的意思。
want to name my files with random numbers. It's again, yeah, it's again, you don't name,
想要用随机数字给我的文件命名。又是这样，是的，又是这样，你不给起名字，
you know, it's let me let me very, very clear here. So from the operating system, from your
你知道，让我非常非常清楚地说一下。所以从操作系统来说，从你的...
application perspective, you open a file and when you open a file, you open food or text
从应用程序的角度来看，当你打开一个文件时，你打开的可以是食物或者文本。
and back, you don't get a file descriptor. So the file descriptors points to a data structure,
并且返回时，你不会得到一个文件描述符。因此，文件描述符指向一个数据结构，
which is open file description. This is in the kernel. You see everything which is below
打开文件描述符。这是在内核中。你可以看到所有在其下的东西。
this dotted line, it's in the kernel. So and here on I shown you this example, I will show
这条虚线，它在内核中。从这里开始，我给你展示这个例子，我会展示
you that this file is a food or text, right? Because this is what you open. But what you
我明白你的意思。你是说这个文件是一个食物还是文本，对吗？因为这是你打开的东西。但是你想表达什么呢？
are saying here is that we really don't want to keep in the open file descriptor food or
你在这里说的是我们真的不想在打开的文件描述符中保存食物或者
text. Instead, I want to keep the I number of the food or text. And the question, why
文本。相反，我想保留食物或文本的编号。还有一个问题，为什么？
do I want to keep I number here in this data structure instead of food or text?
我想在这个数据结构中保留一个数字，而不是食物或文本吗？
File dot text is directory directory independent. OK, that's a very good point. Let's say it's
文件.dot是一个与目录无关的文件。好的，这是一个非常好的观点。我们可以说它是
not food or text is entire past name. Yes, Jasper. Jasper, it's correct. Save the first
不是食物或文本是完整的过去的名字。是的，Jasper。Jasper，是正确的。保存第一个。
translation step. It's exact. You see. I opened the file. And I get the file descriptor, so
翻译步骤。它是准确的。你看。我打开了文件。然后我得到了文件描述符，所以
then. I want if I keep the I number instead of file pass, then I'd save this translation
那么，如果我保留I号而不是文件密码，那么我会保存这个翻译。
step. Otherwise, whenever I'm going to access a file. I need to do this translation because
否则，每当我要访问一个文件时，我都需要进行这个翻译，因为
I have filed a text, I need to do the translation because the I number. So I save this on this
我已经提交了一份文本，我需要进行翻译，因为我是编号。所以我将其保存在这里。
step. Very good. OK, let me just go a little bit quicker. So, yes, you have a file name
步骤。非常好。好的，让我稍微快一点。所以，是的，你有一个文件名。
and in a particular directory, so in a particular directory, you are going the file name is
在一个特定的目录中，所以在一个特定的目录中，你要去的文件名是什么？
going. You can think about it's a it's a bunch of entries in these directories of the file
去吧。你可以把它想象成这些目录中的一堆文件条目。
name offset is by going, going to tell you the offset is going to tell you all the particular
名字偏移是通过前往，前往告诉你偏移将告诉你所有的细节
what is the entry for my particular file. And then for file number, you are going to
什么是我特定文件的条目。然后对于文件号码，你将要做什么？
have file number offset. Basically, this is what it's I number. The I number is you have
有文件号偏移量。基本上，这就是所谓的I号。I号是你所拥有的。
an index structure which is indexed by its of I note each entry in this index structure.
一个索引结构，它是通过I注意到该索引结构中的每个条目进行索引的。
It's an I note which represents all the information associated with that file and the index in
这是一个I注释，代表着与该文件相关的所有信息和索引。
that index structure is the I number. Right, so you have and the open. Operation performed
那个索引结构是I号。对的，所以你有并且打开。执行的操作是什么？
this name resolution, basically translating the file name into the file number and the
这个名字解析，基本上是将文件名翻译成文件编号和
read and write operation are all referring to the file number. So you avoid the first
读取和写入操作都是指向文件编号。因此，你可以避免第一个。
translation step and use a file number as an index to locate the I node and the I node
翻译结果：使用文件号作为索引来定位I节点和I节点的翻译步骤。
is going to lead you to the blocks. We'll see a few examples. So you have three comp
将会带你到方块。我们将看到一些例子。所以你有三个组件。
for components is a directory, the index structure, the storage blocks and free space map. Remember
组件是一个目录，包括索引结构、存储块和空闲空间映射。请记住。
about that. How do you get the file number? You have to look in the directory structure
关于这个问题。你如何获取文件号码？你需要查看目录结构。
in the directory structure. I told you that in directory structure you have entries associated
在目录结构中。我告诉过你，在目录结构中，你有与条目相关联的内容。
with each file. Each entry I didn't tell you what each entry contains, but each entry I'm
随每个文件。每个条目我没有告诉你每个条目包含什么，但每个条目我都是。
telling you now each entry it's a it's a tuple. And which contain its maps the file name to
告诉你现在，每个条目都是一个元组。其中包含将文件名映射到的内容。
the file number. Again, when I'm talking about file number, I am also file number is the
文件编号。再次强调，当我提到文件编号时，我也指的是文件编号是该文件的唯一标识。
same like I number. Okay. This file number can be a file or another directory. Okay.
和我一样。好的。这个文件号可以是一个文件或者另一个目录。好的。
So the operation system stores the mapping in the directory and interprets this format.
所以操作系统将映射存储在目录中，并解释这个格式。
This tuple or the mapping between file name and file number is called directory entry.
这个元组或者文件名和文件号之间的映射被称为目录项。
It's very important to understand like again that the way we manipulate the directory,
这是非常重要的，再次理解我们如何操作目录的方式。
although in Unix a directory just another file is different despite the fact that at
尽管在Unix中，目录只是另一个文件，但它与其他文件不同。
the lower level it's, you know, directory just another file. The way you manipulate
越低的层级，你知道的，只是另一个文件夹。你操作的方式。
the directory is different than the way you manipulate a file. Right. You cannot just
目录与文件的操作方式不同。对的。你不能只是简单地
use the read operation on the file. You can you need to have special operation, redirectory,
使用文件的读取操作。你可以使用特殊操作，重定向。
create directory or make directory and so forth. But let me ask you this question. Why
创建目录或者制作目录等等。但是让我问你一个问题。为什么呢？
don't I want why don't I, you know, again, since as a low level, the directory is just
我不想为什么不呢，你知道的，再说，作为一个低级别的人，目录只是
another file. Why don't I allow the application to do read and write some directories? It's
另一个文件。为什么我不允许应用程序读写一些目录？这是因为
dangerous. Right. You can override if you override these mappings. You're messing up
危险。对的。如果你覆盖这些映射，你可以进行覆盖。你搞砸了。
because these mappings are maintained by the operating system. Right. It's for the same
因为这些映射是由操作系统维护的。对的。这是为了相同的原因。
reason you don't allow the process to arbitrarily modify kernel data structures. That's the
原因是您不允许进程随意修改内核数据结构。这是因为
reason. This is how the directory looks like. Everyone knows that. So directories are typically
理由。这是目录的样子。每个人都知道。所以目录通常是
organized as trees. Directory trees. The leaves in the trees are files. The interior nodes
组织成树形结构。目录树。树中的叶子节点是文件。内部节点
in the trees, including the root are directories. OK. And like I said. You do not allow the
在树中，包括根目录在内都是文件夹。好的。就像我说的。你不允许
application to manipulate, read and write directly on the directories instead to manipulate
应用程序可以直接操作、读取和写入目录，而不是操作其他内容。
directories, you have special function called system calls. Right. Make dear or remove dear.
目录，你有一个特殊的功能叫做系统调用。对的。创建亲爱的或删除亲爱的。
Create a directory or read dear to traverse the directory structures. This is from the
创建一个目录或者读取亲爱的来遍历目录结构。这是来自的。
command line you can use from the command line, but you also can use them. You have
命令行可以从命令行使用，但你也可以使用它们。你有什么问题吗？
libc support. You can have also use a library so you can use this programmatically. From
libc支持。您还可以使用一个库，以便可以以编程方式使用它。从
your application link and unlink. This allows you to actually break actually this hierarchy.
您的应用程序链接和取消链接。这样您就可以真正打破这种层次结构。
And actually you can have a name of a file. You can have a file, a name pointing to an
实际上，你可以给一个文件起一个名字。你可以有一个文件，一个指向该文件的名字。
existing file. Right. So you have a file with a name say foo.txt. Now I can have another
现有文件。对的。所以你有一个名为foo.txt的文件。现在我可以有另一个文件。
name called foo1.txt pointing to the same file. We'll learn more about that. So just
名为foo1.txt的文件指向同一个文件。我们将会更多地了解这个。所以只需要
to give you a sense now, let's assume that about the overhead which are involved, let's
给你一个概念，现在假设涉及到的开销。让我们先假设一下涉及到的开销。
assume that we want to access to resolve this. To get the I number of the file count. Right.
假设我们想要访问以解决这个问题。获取文件计数的I号码。对吗？
And then to access the file count. So what do we need to do here? First of all, we need
然后要访问文件计数。那么我们在这里需要做什么？首先，我们需要
to locate the root of the directory. We need to start searching from somewhere from the
开始搜索目录的根目录。我们需要从某个地方开始搜索。
root of the directory. And the root, how do we do that? Well, fortunately, by convention,
目录的根目录。那么，根目录，我们怎么做呢？幸运的是，按照惯例，
the operating system puts the file system, puts the root directory, the root in a fixed
操作系统将文件系统放在根目录下，将根目录放在一个固定的位置。
position on the disk. So you access this block, data block for root. In the data blocks, the
位置在磁盘上。因此，您可以访问此块，即根目录的数据块。在数据块中，
root you have, you have this kind of directory entries, file entries in the directory, in
你有根目录，你有这种类型的目录条目，目录中的文件条目。
the root directory. So you are going to have to locate my. Right. How you do that? You
根目录。所以你需要找到我的位置。对吗？你要怎么做呢？
can linear research. Typically, the number of entries in the directory is small. Now,
可以进行线性研究。通常，目录中的条目数量很少。现在，
once you locate my, you read the file header for my, because how do you know that? Because
一旦你找到我的位置，你就读取我的文件头，因为你怎么知道呢？因为
the entry for my tells you what is the file number for directory my. So from that, you
can determine the specific file number for the directory named "my".
go and read it. Read again the first data block in my. And you search for the book.
去读一下。再读一遍我的第一个数据块。然后你去找那本书。
The third my is going to gain, it's a directory, it's going to keep a bunch of directory
第三个我的是要获取的，它是一个目录，将保存一堆目录。
file entries. You read the header for the book again, you find book. The book entry,
文件条目。你再次阅读书籍的标题，你发现书籍。书籍条目，
the book entry is going to have the file number associated with the book directory. You use
这本书的条目将与书目录关联的文件号一起使用。您可以使用它。
that in order to read the header for book. And then you read the first data block for
为了读取书的标题，你需要先读取第一个数据块。
book. You search for count. You find count and the count is you get the file number for
书。你搜索计数。你找到计数，计数就是你得到的文件编号。
count. There is a file header for count and now you are done. So how many accesses? One,
计数。有一个用于计数的文件头，现在你完成了。那么有多少次访问？一次，
two, three, four, five, six, seven. Just to do this resolution. So now you see how important
二、三、四、五、六、七。只是为了完成这个决议。所以现在你看到了多么重要。
is to keep in the description of the file to keep the number, the number or the file
将文件的描述保留为数字、编号或文件名。
number instead of just the file name. Because I save the next time after I open it, the
数字而不仅仅是文件名。因为我在打开后保存下一次，所以
next time when I do a read and write, I save seven accesses. And that is that expensive.
下一次当我进行读写操作时，我可以节省七次访问。而那是非常昂贵的。
So as you know, you also have the notion of current directories and the current directories,
所以你知道，你也有当前目录和当前目录的概念。
if you just refer to the file name without ignoring the past name, you are referring
如果你只是提到文件名而没有忽略之前的名称，那么你正在引用。
that you assume that in the current directory. The current directory, it's already cached.
你假设在当前目录中。当前目录已经被缓存。
So it's one way to reduce this number of counts. So this is how happened, you know, the file
所以这是减少计数的一种方法。这就是发生的方式，你知道，这个文件。
structure in the memory. And this is a user space, a kernel memory, and it's a secondary
内存中的结构。这是一个用户空间，一个内核内存，它是一个次要的。
story. This is what happened on the disk. So you have read, when you read a file descriptor,
故事。这是发生在磁盘上的事情。所以你已经读过了，当你读取一个文件描述符时，
this file descriptor paying points into this per process open file table. Each of these
文件描述符将支付点数到每个进程的打开文件表中。其中每个
entries, it's information associated with that file. And what you are going to get here
条目，它是与该文件相关联的信息。而你在这里将要得到的是什么。
is a file number and the position, the seek position of the current position in the file.
文件号是指当前文件的编号和位置，即文件中的当前位置。
You see this gray thing here, it's again this entry. Let me show you just to connect the
你看到这个灰色的东西，又是这个入口。让我给你看一下，只是为了连接。
dots. Oops. Is this one? The information in that gray area is this open file description.
点。哎呀。这是一个吗？那个灰色区域中的信息是这个打开文件的描述。
Right, the I number and the position in the file. Okay, so this is what is here. So the
好的，I号和文件中的位置。好的，这是这里的内容。所以
I number points you to the I node. This is the open file tables and the I node has protection
我将你指向I节点。这是打开文件表，而I节点具有保护机制。
bits and then also has all this, maintains all these data blocks. And all this is maintained,
位元，然后还有所有这些，维护所有这些数据块。而所有这些都是被维护的，
is maintained also on the disk. The I node information is maintained on the disk because
维护在磁盘上。I节点信息维护在磁盘上是因为
it maintains the association between that file number and the blocks, data blocks, where
它维护了该文件编号与块（数据块）之间的关联。
the data of the file is located. So it must be on the disk, it must be durable because
文件的数据所在位置。所以它必须在磁盘上，它必须是持久的，因为
it must persist after you finish your program, after the program ends. Okay. We talk about
这必须在你完成程序之后持续存在，即在程序结束后。好的。我们来谈谈。
all of these things. I'm going to end up with this, a few interesting data and then we are
所有这些东西。我最终会得到这个，一些有趣的数据，然后我们就完成了。
going to continue next time with the file system. So this is a study which was 13, 14
下次将继续讲解文件系统。所以这是一个关于13、14年的研究。
years ago, but it still is very relevant. And this is the point here is the following.
几年前，但它仍然非常相关。这里的重点是以下内容。
So what this study is looking, it's looking over five years and it's looking about how
这项研究的目的是什么，它会持续五年，主要研究的内容是什么？
the distribution of the file lengths and other information about statistics about the files
文件长度的分布以及其他关于文件统计的信息
in a file system. The first important one is basically show you what is the size of
在一个文件系统中。第一个重要的是基本上展示给你的是文件的大小是多少。
the file, the distribution of the file sizes for a file system. And basically what this
文件，文件系统中文件大小的分布。基本上这是什么意思？
tells you, this is on the X axis, the file size and the number of files on the Y axis.
告诉你，这是X轴，文件大小和文件数量在Y轴上。
So this is for different currencies for different years. So you have something similar, although
这是关于不同年份的不同货币。所以你有类似的东西，尽管
as years pass, you have more and more files. And the main point here is this is showing
随着岁月的流逝，你拥有的文件越来越多。而这里的主要观点是这在展示着什么。
that most of the files are small, not that the X axis is log scale. So these are very
大部分文件都很小，并不是X轴是对数刻度。所以这些都是非常
small, right? For instance, most of the files are 512 kilobytes or less. There are very
小的，对吧？例如，大部分文件都是512千字节或更小。非常少量的文件大小超过这个限制。
few large files. So most of the files are small files. However, if you look at, if I'm
少量大文件。所以大部分文件都是小文件。然而，如果你看一下，如果我...
taking some piece of data and I'm asking the question from the files, from all the file
提取一些数据，并从文件中提出问题，从所有文件中提出问题。
system, I'm taking a piece of data and I'm asking the question, what is the size of the
系统，我正在获取一段数据，并且我想问一个问题，这段数据的大小是多少？
file? Which contains this piece of data? Then this is the answer I'm going to get. I'm going
文件？其中包含这段数据？那么这就是我要得到的答案。我要得到的答案是什么。
to get, and basically you see now that most of the data is contained in big files. So
获取，并且基本上你现在可以看到大部分数据都包含在大文件中。所以
yes, the majority of files is small. But the big files are responsible for most of the
是的，大部分文件都很小。但是大文件占据了大部分的责任。
data. Okay. And I am going to end up with a question to you. It's a fun question. You
数据。好的。我要问你一个问题。这是一个有趣的问题。你
see, you see here that on this kind of distribution, you have two peaks. You have a peak around
看，你看到这种分布上有两个峰值。你会发现一个峰值在...
two megabytes and another peak around one gigabyte. Right? So you have, why do you think
两兆字节，另外还有一个峰值约为一千兆字节。对吗？所以你有，你认为为什么呢？
you have these two peaks? Why do you think this one gigabyte? What do you think causes
你有这两个峰值吗？为什么你认为这一个千兆字节？你认为是什么原因导致的？
it? And by the way, in 2000, it wasn't such a peak, but as the time goes on, passed, you
是吗？顺便说一下，在2000年的时候，它并不是那么高峰，但随着时间的推移，过去了，你
have this peak. Yes. Let's see. Yes. That sounds very good answers here, right? Yes.
有这个高峰。是的。让我们看看。是的。这听起来非常好，对吗？是的。
Video, right? It's like, especially that was peer to peer system and you read about it.
视频，对吧？就是那种特别的点对点系统，你读过相关的资料。
Yes. This is one reason it's media. The other reason this is a lot bigger and bigger files.
是的。这是其中一个原因，它是媒体。另一个原因是文件越来越大。
These are also binary files. So the executive become bigger over time. That's excellent
这些也是二进制文件。所以随着时间的推移，执行文件会变得越来越大。这太棒了。
answers. Okay. So with this, we are going to stop here. Again, good luck to the midterm
答案。好的。所以，我们就到这里结束吧。再次祝你期中考试好运。
tomorrow and I'll see you again on a Saturday. Thank you.
明天我会再次在星期六见到你。谢谢。
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[空白音频]